Guide to the School of Pharmacy Photograph Collection 1916-1948
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
School of Pharmacy Photograph Collection
1916-1948
1920-1935
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center Special Collections & Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu
P 166
Oregon State College. School of Pharmacy.
0.05 cubic foot, including 85 photographs 2 boxes
The School of Pharmacy Photograph Collection consists of images assembled by the School of Pharmacy and by Ernst Stuhr that depict the Pharmacy Building, pharmacy classrooms and laboratories, and exhibits for drug shows at Oregon State College. Pharmacy instruction began at Oregon Agricultural college in 1898; Ernst Stuhr was a member of the pharmacy faculty from 1927 to 1944.
Historical Note:
The Course in Pharmacy was established at Oregon Agricultural College in 1898 with a four-year program leading to a B.S. degree in pharmacy, at a time when most pharmaceutical curricula were only 2-year programs. In 1951, Oregon State College inaugurated a five-year curriculum leading to a B.S. degree in pharmacy -- nine years before the five-year curriculum became the minimum requirement for all U.S. pharmacy schools. In 1999, the College of Pharmacy began offering a four-year entry-level Doctor of Pharmacy (Pharm.D.) instead of a B.S. degree.
Ernst Thedore Stuhr served on the faculty of the Oregon State College (OSC) School of Pharmacy from 1927 to 1944 as Assistant Professor of Pharmacy (1927-1930) and Associate Professor (1930-1944) of Pharmacology and Pharmacognosy. His major area of research, medicinal plants, was reflected in the many articles that he wrote for scholarly and trade journals.
The School of Pharmacy Photograph Collection consists of images assembled by the School of Pharmacy and by Ernst Stuhr. The photographs depict the Pharmacy Building, model drugstore, pharmacy classrooms and laboratories, and exhibits at drug shows held on the Oregon State campus. Many of the images include pharmacy students. Also of note are several images of the Eli Lilly drug manufacturing facilities in Indianapolis, Indiana, in the 1920s.
Several of the photographs were made by Howells Studio in Corvallis; images by Ball Studio (Corvallis) and Photo Art Commercial Studios (Portland) are also included.
The bulk of the collection is photograph prints; several nitrate negatives are also included.
Collection is open for research.
The School of Pharmacy Photograph Collection consists of two series: I. School of Pharmacy Photographs, 1916-1948 and II. Ernst Stuhr Photographs, 1930-1935.
The photographs that comprise Series I were received by the University Archives in the late 1960s or 1970s. The Ernst Stuhr photographs were received by the University Archives in 1981 with other Ernst Stuhr materials that are now described as the Ernst Thedore Stuhr Papers.
Additional photographs of pharmacy students, faculty, and facilities are available in Harriet's Collection, the Adolph Ziefle Photographs (P 076), and the Leo Sciuchetti Collection. The College of Pharmacy Records (RG 105) provide information about pharmacy instruction at Oregon State. The Ernst Thedore Stuhr Papers document Stuhr's research and writing on medicinal plants and the pharmacy profession.
Stuhr, Ernst T. (Ernst Thedore), 1900-1980.; Stuhr, Ernst T. (Ernst Thedore), 1900-1980.
Oregon Agricultural College. Department of Pharmacy.; Oregon Agricultural College. School of Pharmacy.; Oregon Agricultural College--Students.; Oregon State College--Students.; Eli Lilly and Company.; Ball Studio.; Howell's Studio.
Drug factories--Indiana.; Pharmacognosy--Oregon--Corvallis.; Pharmacy colleges--Oregon--Corvallis.; Pharmacy--Study and teaching (Higher)--Oregon--Corvallis.
Nitrate negatives.; Photographic prints.
Colleges and Universities; Medicine and Health; Science; Oregon; Corvallis; Photographs
- School of Pharmacy Photographs, 1916-1948; Series I; 68 prints and 3 nitrate negatives
  Series I consists of photographs assembled by the School of Pharmacy depicting the Pharmacy Building, model drugstore, classrooms and laboratories, and exhibits at drug shows. Pharmacy students are shown in many of the photographs. Also of note are several images of the Eli Lilly drug manufacturing facility in Indianapolis.
  - Model drugstore, circa 1940; P166:01-P166:03 (Box 1)
    One print includes (from left to right): Ed Greyerbiehl, Lillian Polson, William Donald Fowler, James Bidgood, Bob Berman, Jack Kadau, Wade Stuart, John McPherson, Peyton Hawes, Ronald Esson, and Alberta Wilson (back to camera).
  - School of Pharmacy building, circa 1924-1945; P166:04-P166:10 (Box 1)
    Includes several views of the building under construction and one line drawing of the building.
  - Pharmacy graduates, 1920; P166:11 (Box 1)
    Composite print of individual portraits of graduates and faculty. Also includes images of President W.J. Kerr. Photograph by Ball Studio.
  - Pharmacy alumni, 1948; P166:12 (Box 1)
    Includes Frank Henry and Fred Meek. Photograph by Photo Art Commercial Studios in Portland, Oregon.
  - Ernest Beals in laboratory, circa 1940; P166:13 (Box 1)
  - Pharmacy class on annual trip to Blumauer Frank Drug Company, a wholesale drug house in Portland, 1916; P166:14 (Box 1)
  - Pharmacy classrooms, circa 1930; P166:15-P166:17 (Box 1)
    Includes one image of pharmacognosy classroom and museum.
  - Student doing demonstrations at drug show, 1925; P166:18 (Box 1)
    Photograph by Howells Studio.
  - Pharmacy laboratories, circa 1925-1940; P166:19-P166:24 (Box 1)
    One image depicts Howard Pertulla, who graduated in 1940; another shows Ernst Stuhr with students.
  - Pharmacy exhibits and displays, circa 1925-1940; P166:25-P166:52
    - Displays of pharmaceutical and chemical equipment and procedures, P166:25-P166:36 (Box 1)
    - View of crude laboratory; a part of a course in pharmacognosy, circa 1925; P166:37 (Box 1)
    - Household drug cabinet, circa 1940; P166:38 (Box 1)
    - Pharmacy exhibit at Home Economics building, P166:39; print and nitrate negative (Box 1, 2)
    - Pharmacy exhibit at Home Economics building, P166:40 (Box 1)
      Includes Johnson & Johnson wholesale exhibit.
    - Drug show at Home Economics building, P166:41; print and nitrate negative (Box 1, 2)
    - Pharmacy exhibit, P166:42; print and nitrate negative (Box 1, 2)
      Showing commercial and scientific departments.
    - Pharmacy exhibit by University of Minnesota College of Pharmacy, 1928; P166:43 (Box 1)
    - Exhibits at Drug Show, 1931; P166:44-P166:52 (Box 1)
      Several photographs by Howells Studio. One image includes Ernst Stuhr. Several sample window displays for cosmetics are depicted.
  - Drug factories, 1919-1928; P166:53-P166:62 (Box 1)
    One image is from Parke, Davis & Company in Detroit, Michigan. Most of the photographs are of the Eli Lilly factory in Indianapolis, Indiana. These images depict the bottling department, labeling and wrapping liquids, the elixer and extract departments, filling liquids in small quantities, sugar coating, iletin finishing, capsule filling, and vacuum stills.
  - Military Science and Tactics exhibit, circa 1925; P166:63 (Box 1)
  - Home Economics Building, circa 1920; P166:64 (Box 1)
    With a temporary sign, Home Economics Pharmacy, over the entrance.
  - Chemistry laboratory, circa 1920; P166:65 (Box 1)
  - Food Products laboratory, circa 1920; P166:66 (Box 1)
    Laboratory for analysis of food products and the testing of ingredients in prescriptions and proprietaries.
  - Fish Technology laboratory, circa 1920; P166:67 (Box 1)
    Studying fish oils from salmon cannery to utilize by-products.
- Ernst Stuhr Photographs, 1930-1935; Series II; 14 prints
  Series II consists of photographs assembled by Ernst Stuhr. The images depict a series of exhibits on pharmaceutical topics, including glandular extracts and tuberculosis, and the attendees at a plant science seminar at Oregon State College. Several of the photographs are by Howells Studio; one is by Ball Studio. All are photographic prints.
  - Apothecarie Shoppe exhibit, circa 1930; P166:68 (Box 1)
    Depicted in the image are five men. Standing in the doorway, second from left, is Henry DeBoest.
  - Exhibits For Your Health's Sake and Experiemental Animals Innoculated with T.B., circa 1930; P166:69 (Box 1)
  - Various exhibits, circa 1930; P166:70 (Box 1)
    Exhibits pictured include Cathartics, Glandular Extracts, and For Your Health's Sake.
  - Exhibit: Crepe Decorations Donated by Dennison Mfg. Co., circa 1930; P166:71 (Box 1)
  - Various exhibits, circa 1930; P166:72 (Box 1)
    Exhibits pictured include Milk Foods & Modifiers, Digestants, Heart Tonics & Stimulants, Skin Affection, Antiseptics & Disinfectants, and The Source of Insulin.
  - Exhibit: Interior of Pharmacy Shop, circa 1930; P166:73 (Box 1)
  - Exhibit: Crude Drug Specimens, circa 1931; P166:74 (Box 1)
  - Various exhibits, circa 1931; P166:75 (Box 1)
  - Various exhibits, circa 1931; P166:76 (Box 1)
    Exhibits pictured include Surgical Supplies and Gland Therapy.
  - Various exhibits, circa 1931; P166:77 (Box 1)
    Exhibits pictured include Evolution of Rubber, Crude Drug Specimens, For Your Health's Sake, Prescription Compounding, and Infusum Digitalis.
  - Various exhibits, circa 1931; P166:78 (Box 1)
    Exhibits pictured include Organic Chemicals, Commerical Pharmacy, Retail Selling, and others. E.T. Stuhr is depicted on the right.
  - Interior of pharmacy, 1931; P166:79 (Box 1)
    Drugs and customer counter pictured.
  - Exhibit Effects of Molecular Weight, P166:80 (Box 1)
  - Plant Science Seminar members in front of Pharmacy Building, circa 1935; P166:81 (Box 1)
    Individuals identified in this image include F.A. Gilfillan, back row first on left; Dean A. Ziefle, back row fourth from left; and Ernst T. Stuhr front row first on left. Photograph by Ball Studio.